<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Notes and Bits of Kisun Pokharel</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Notes and Bits of Kisun Pokharel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene expression and regulation (2cp)</title>
      <link>/2019/11/28/gene-expression-and-regulation-2cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/28/gene-expression-and-regulation-2cp/</guid>
      <description>RNA sequencing: the teenage years Roy Stark et al. 2012 (26pp)
Genome Regulation by Long Noncoding RNAs. John L. Rinn and Howard Y. Chang Annual Review of Biochemistry Vol. 81:145-166 (Volume publication date July 2012) https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-biochem-051410-092902 (21 pp)
Non-coding RNAs in Development and Disease: Background, Mechanisms, and Therapeutic Approaches Julia Beermann, Maria-Teresa Piccoli, Janika Viereck, and Thomas Thum 17 AUG 2016https://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.00041.2015 (29 pp)
Long non‐coding RNA regulation of reproduction and development David H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embryonic diapause (1cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/embryonic-diapause-1cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/embryonic-diapause-1cp/</guid>
      <description>Diapause. Marilyn B Renfree, Geoffrey Shaw. 2000. Annual Review of Physiology Vol. 62:353-375 link (23pp)
Embryonic Diapause Is Conserved across Mammals. Grazyna E. Ptak ,Emanuela Tacconi,Marta Czernik,Paola Toschi,Jacek A. Modlinski,Pasqualino Loi. 2012, Plos One. link (7pp)
The enigma of embryonic diapause. Marilyn B. Renfree, Jane C. Fenelon. 2017. Development. 144: 3199-3210; link (12pp)
Embryonic diapause and its regulation.Flavia L Lopes, Joëlle and Bruce D Murphy. 2004. 128(6):669–678 [link]{https://rep.bioscientifica.com/view/journals/rep/128/6/1280669.xml} (9pp)
The history of the discovery of embryonic diapause in mammals Jane C Fenelon, Marilyn B Renfree Biology of Reproduction, Volume 99, Issue 1, July 2018, Pages 242–251 [link]{https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene Control (3cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/gene-control-3cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/gene-control-3cp/</guid>
      <description>Whole book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetics of Reproduction in Sheep (2cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/genetics-of-reproduction-in-sheep-2cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/genetics-of-reproduction-in-sheep-2cp/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1: Selection for litter size, GE Bradford, 15pp
Chapter 2: Crossbreeding for fecundity, W.J. Boylan, 4 pp
Chapter 3: Evaluation and utilization of Finnsheep, L.D Young et al., 14pp
Chapter 10: Genetic and maternal effects on sheep reproduction and their influence on slection, G. Nitter, 10pp
Chapter 16: Utilization of major genes, Charles smith, 8pp
Chapter 19: Linear programming model for incorporating the boorola gene into another breed, J.M. Elsen et al, 8pp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomic imprinting (0.5cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/genomic-imprinting-0.5cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/genomic-imprinting-0.5cp/</guid>
      <description>Reviewed articles Genomic imprinting in mammals. Denise P. Barlow et al 2014, Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 20pp
Genomic imprinting and parent-of-origin effects on complex traits. Heather A. Lawson et al. 2013, Nature Reviews Genetis, (10pp)
Genomic imprinting: the emergence of an epigenetic paradigm.Anne C. Ferguson-Smith, 2011 (12pp)
write more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ovulation (1cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/ovulation-1cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/ovulation-1cp/</guid>
      <description>Regulation of ovulation rate in mmamals: contribution of sheep genetic models. Stephane Fabre et al. 2006 (12pp)
A review of the effects of supplementary nutrition in the ewe on the concentrations of reproductive and metabolic hormones and the mechanisms that regulate folliculogenesis and ovulation rate. Scaramuzzi RJ1, Campbell BK, Downing JA, Kendall NR, Khalid M, Muñoz-Gutiérrez M, Somchit A. Reprod Nutr Dev. 2006 Jul-Aug;46(4):339-54. Epub 2006 Jul 7. (16pp)
Regulation of folliculogenesis and the determination of ovulation rate in ruminants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physiology of Reproduction (2cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/physiology-of-reproduction-2cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/physiology-of-reproduction-2cp/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 21, Follicular development in mouse, sheep and human models (49 pp) Chapter 22, Ovulation (25pp) Chapter 23, Structure, Function and Regulation of the corpus luteum (54pp) Chapter 27, Control ovarian cycle of the sheep (47pp) Chapter 38, Embryo Implantation (43pp) Chapter 52, Epigenetics of Reproduction (63pp)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>preimplantation (1.5 cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/preimplantation-1.5-cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/preimplantation-1.5-cp/</guid>
      <description>The contribution of the maternal immune system to the establishment of pregnancy in cattle link to article (8pp)
Bridging endometrial receptivity and implantation: network of hormones, cytokines, and growth factors. Singh M1, Chaudhry P, Asselin E. J Endocrinol. 2011 Jul;210(1):5-14. doi: 10.1530/JOE-10-0461. Epub 2011 Mar 3. (9pp)
Comparative aspects of implantation. Bazer FW1, Spencer TE, Johnson GA, Burghardt RC, Wu G.Reproduction. 2009 Aug;138(2):195-209. doi: 10.1530/REP-09-0158. Epub 2009 Jun 5. (14pp)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>