<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review articles on Notes and Bits of Kisun Pokharel</title>
    <link>/categories/review-articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review articles on Notes and Bits of Kisun Pokharel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/review-articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene expression and regulation (2cp)</title>
      <link>/2019/11/28/gene-expression-and-regulation-2cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/28/gene-expression-and-regulation-2cp/</guid>
      <description>RNA sequencing: the teenage years Roy Stark et al. 2012 (26pp)
Genome Regulation by Long Noncoding RNAs. John L. Rinn and Howard Y. Chang Annual Review of Biochemistry Vol. 81:145-166 (Volume publication date July 2012) https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-biochem-051410-092902 (21 pp)
Non-coding RNAs in Development and Disease: Background, Mechanisms, and Therapeutic Approaches Julia Beermann, Maria-Teresa Piccoli, Janika Viereck, and Thomas Thum 17 AUG 2016https://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.00041.2015 (29 pp)
Long non‐coding RNA regulation of reproduction and development David H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embryonic diapause (1cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/embryonic-diapause-1cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/embryonic-diapause-1cp/</guid>
      <description>Diapause. Marilyn B Renfree, Geoffrey Shaw. Annual Review of Physiology. 2000 link (23pp)
Embryonic Diapause Is Conserved across Mammals. Grazyna E. Ptak ,Emanuela Tacconi,Marta Czernik,Paola Toschi,Jacek A. Modlinski,Pasqualino Loi. PLOS One. 2012 link (7pp)
The enigma of embryonic diapause. Marilyn B. Renfree, Jane C. Fenelon. Development. 2017 link (12pp)
Embryonic diapause and its regulation. Lopes FL, Desmarais JA, Murphy BD. Reproduction. 2004 link (9pp)
The history of the discovery of embryonic diapause in mammals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomic imprinting (0.5cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/genomic-imprinting-0.5cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/genomic-imprinting-0.5cp/</guid>
      <description>Reviewed articles Genomic imprinting in mammals. Denise P. Barlow et al 2014, Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 20pp
Genomic imprinting and parent-of-origin effects on complex traits. Heather A. Lawson et al. 2013, Nature Reviews Genetis, (10pp)
Genomic imprinting: the emergence of an epigenetic paradigm.Anne C. Ferguson-Smith, 2011 (12pp)
write more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ovulation (1cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/ovulation-1cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/ovulation-1cp/</guid>
      <description>Summary Based on the following   Regulation of ovulation rate in mmamals: contribution of sheep genetic models. Fabre S, Pierre A, Mulsant P, Bodin L, Pasquale ED, Persani L, Monget P, Monniaux D. Reproductive Biology and Endocrinology. 2006 link (12pp)
  A review of the effects of supplementary nutrition in the ewe on the concentrations of reproductive and metabolic hormones and the mechanisms that regulate folliculogenesis and ovulation rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>preimplantation (1.5 cp)</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/preimplantation-1.5-cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/preimplantation-1.5-cp/</guid>
      <description>Summary Based on the following review articles   The contribution of the maternal immune system to the establishment of pregnancy in cattle. Trudee F. Frontiers in Immunology. 2015 link (8pp)
  Bridging endometrial receptivity and implantation: network of hormones, cytokines, and growth factors. Singh M1, Chaudhry P, Asselin E. Journal of Endocrinology. 2011 link (9pp)
  Comparative aspects of implantation.Bazer FW, Spencer TE, Johnson GA, Burghardt RC, Wu G.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>